[Bloom Life]
[2007]
I see a pilaf vendor over there.
Pilaf. I love pilaf!
Let's go.
Dad,
why are there
so many people in the bazaar?
Because in our Kashgar,
the bazaar is like a father,
and also a mother.
Anything can happen in the bazaar.
Thank you.
Lamb leg pilaf.
Let me see.
Look, what's this?
A sheep knucklebone.
Then break it open for me to see.
Okay.
Here you go.
One for each of us.
Right, one for each of us.
[Episode 2: Those Who Left
and Those Who Stayed]
One, two, three, four.
Five, six, seven, eight.
Two, two, three, four.
Three, two, three, four.
Five, six, seven, eight.
Stop.
Alright, let's take a break.
Your feet are bleeding.
Can you still wear high heels?
Let me tell you,
they suddenly announced today
the casting for the lead actress
of Alip and Sänäm.
Sänäm is the role
I've wanted to play since I was a child.
If I wear flat shoes,
how can I outshine those new girls?
You‘re just looking for trouble.
Why are you dressed
in the same color as the ancient city?
These are Morandi colors.
They are very classy.
Looks like a sandstorm.
How is it?
Compared to those fresh graduates,
I can still hold my own, right?
You're the star of your troupe.
Why are you comparing yourself
to a bunch of little girls?
You don't understand.
Alright,
you couldn't be any prettier.
Girls!
For our troupe's revival of
"Alip and Sänäm",
besides showing
Sänäm's brave side,
we must also give it a contemporary feel.
We need to focus on
portraying her as a woman
with a spirit of self-pursuit.
Technically speaking,
we
will focus on using spins
to express her rebellion against fate.
Good. Keep it up.
Come on, girls.
Look alive.
Good.
Keep it up.
Dad.
Can we not let Mulading
fill out the forms anymore?
His handwriting is so crooked,
even a sheep could write better.
Others can't read it,
and they send it back for me to redo.
Is it wrong for him
to help you fill out the forms?
Without him in the house,
I would've died of exhaustion long ago.
Then you can teach me to make earthenware.
I promise I'll do it better
and faster than him.
How can a woman
make earthenware?
Women can wash clothes and cook.
Why can't they make earthenware?
No way.
Laili, you're back.
I bought some figs.
Try some.
Mom!
Mom,
why did you let him wash my clothes?
I didn't look carefully.
I hid them under my pillow on purpose.
I said I'd wash them myself.
An apprentice is like a son.
He is filial to his master.
So we should treat him
like family.
Even so,
family doesn't mean-
What's the fuss?
You'll marry him sooner or later.
When did I say I'd marry him?
Stop the fuss.
Great job, Minawar.
Good.
You didn't embarrass the veterans.
Back then, you relied on
this eight-beat spinning trick
to join our troupe.
You still have the skills.
Good job.
Minawar danced so well.
Yes, she's amazing.
It has to be Minawar.
She's so stable even in high heels.
She's truly our star.
I was just doing what I had to.
Band-Aids and plasters are in the drawer.
Take it easy.
Okay.
I'll pack and send the pots later.
Sorry.
What's going on here?
He hit you. It's him.
Sorry.
I-I didn't mean to.
I was playing football with them.
Anyway, the ball didn't hit me.
You hit me.
What should I do?
You tell me.
Pay for it then.
How much?
600.
Okay.
600 it is.
Sorry.
I didn't bring any money
or my phone today.
I...
You didn't bring money.
Are you kidding me?
Wait a minute.
I'll leave this bag with you as a deposit.
What's this?
These are my tools for making instruments.
Then where can I find you?
Adijiang Instrument Shop.
I live there.
Come, sit inside.
Come, please sit inside.
No, thanks.
Come inside.
Dear guests,
you've been sitting here for a while
without ordering anything.
Are you waiting for someone?
Or is there something else?
Go ask Adili about this.
So you're Adili's friends.
Adili?
He went out driving.
He hasn't come back yet.
What do you want with Adili?
Adili borrowed
some money from our company.
Today is the day the money is due.
Look.
We know about the contract,
but he hasn't come back.
And we can't contact him either.
How about you...
There's no other options.
The contract is very clear.
Today, either you give me the money,
or this shop belongs to me.
Will they give us the money today?
Today, either we get the money
or we get the shop.
I'll mortgage these to you first.
My son will definitely
pay you back when he returns.
Just these?
Let's go.
Good afternoon.
You're in such a hurry to leave?
Yeah.
-Work won't wait for me.
-Let me.
I'll do it.
-Give it to me.
-Didn't you get fired?
That's not certain yet.
I can still try.
Why do people try so hard
to become a piece of a jigsaw puzzle?
What do you mean?
If I were you,
I wouldn't go to work.
I'd rather be the missing piece
in the puzzle.
Good for you.
Only you care about
the finer things in life.
My finer things are right here.
I'm here to open a homestay.
Okay. Just don't open it
next to our house.
Arzugul,
tell me,
if you're not comfortable living there,
I will clear out
the biggest room on the second floor
for you, okay?
Uncle, I live very well up there.
I still have things to do in the company,
so I have to go back quickly.
I'll go back and spend time with my mom
and leave tomorrow or the day after.
You-
Sweetie,
work can be done anytime, right?
Arzugul, you came back from Shanghai
and haven't even eaten my almond tart yet.
Grandma,
I don't want to leave either.
But the company is pushing hard.
You finally came back once.
Why don't you
spend more time with Grandma?
Can the company not run without you?
Your troupe can't run without you, right?
Your foot is swollen like that,
but you still have to dance in high heels.
Arzugul,
You finally came back to Kashgar
from Shanghai.
Don't you buy some gifts
for your colleagues?
Minawar,
today is the grand bazaar.
You take Arzugul
there for a walk.
I...
have to go back to the troupe later.
It's fine, I know the way.
I can go by myself.
Minawar,
didn't you say
you were going to the bazaar
to buy things this afternoon?
Why haven't you left yet?
No.
Look at the time.
They're closing soon.
Go now.
It's running late.
I've told you since you were little
that you should dress up nicely
when visiting the bazaar.
Look at you now.
Here.
Uncle.
Let me do it.
Alright.
Here you go.
I'm on a diet. I don't drink sweet things.
Are you really here to buy things?
Have you been away for too long
and forgotten it?
When us women visit the bazaar,
it's mainly to show off
our beauty and clothes.
Buying things is just an excuse.
Did you bring perfume?
What's this smell?
Woody scent.
You might as well plant a tree at home
instead of wearing this.
When you wear perfume,
it should be floral.
Like walking into a garden.
I heard your house is built.
Over 20,000 a square meter.
So expensive.
I'll take you to see
our new house someday.
The best neighborhood in Kashgar.
We bought 300 to 400 square meters.
How big is yours?
Over 60 square meters.
That's so small.
I really don't know
what you're after in Shanghai.
We don't have
to force a conversation.
How about we go our separate ways?
Sure.
Where can I buy a Yengisar knife?
Let's go, I'll show you around.
Come take a look.
Handmade Yengisar knives.
Come take a look, beauties.
Handmade knives.
Let me see this one.
Okay, beauty.
How much is this one?
800.
You're Minawar's friend,
I'll give you a discount.
660.
Alright.
Since Minawar said so,
it's a deal.
Wait a minute.
I just threw out a number.
I'm not the one buying.
It's fine.
660 it is.
For good luck.
Are you crazy?
Spending 600 on a knife.
Does money grow on trees for you?
I'm giving it to a client.
Of course I have to buy a nice one.
When did you become so tactful?
Just doing what it takes to make a living.
Come take a look.
A batch of amazing
tumbler pigeons arrived today.
They're so incredible that once they fly,
they can do 6 or 7 somersaults in a row.
Come take a look.
A batch of amazing
tumbler pigeons arrived today.
They're so incredible that once they fly,
they can do 6 or 7 somersaults in a row.
Then they dive straight down,
and when they're
just 6 cm from the ground,
they can suddenly fly back up.
If you don't like it,
you don't have to pay.
What I brought today
are all top-notch goods.
Thank you.
Put my hat down.
Friend,
are you buying pigeons?
Come here, look.
These pigeons of mine,
when they fly into the sky,
they can do 7 or 8 somersaults.
And when they almost hit the ground,
they fly back up.
They also know the way.
They know the way.
No matter how far they fly,
if you blow this whistle,
they'll fly right back.
Re-really?
Of course it's true, friend.
Friend,
since your pigeons are so amazing,
can they help me find someone
in this bazaar?
Friend,
you can just buy it.
These are not eagles.
How can they find someone for you?
Come take a look.
Help!
Xia Zi!
Are you okay, Xia Zi?
I'm fine.
Are you hurt anywhere?
What's wrong with you?
If you don't watch your sheep,
what if they hurt someone?
Xia Zi.
Fang Nan.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Why is it you?
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Have you ever imagined
Have some.
Sure.
the scene of reuniting
with your first love after years apart?
I've rehearsed it countless times.
A chance encounter at a street corner,
a class reunion
where everyone has their own agenda,
or someone's wedding,
or even
someone's funeral.
When I saw Fang Nan again at the bazaar,
I thought this was the most reasonable.
The bazaar is like a father,
and also a mother.
The bazaar is everything in the world.
So, of course, anything
can happen in the bazaar.
Oh, stop wiping.
You can't wipe it off.
You have to wash it.
That...
should be cow dung.
It can be rubbed off with water.
Do you want to go
wash it off in my sheepfold?
You have a sheepfold?
What are you doing now?
I sell sheep.
My sheepfold
is right on the way back to the city.
I remember you went to Urumqi for college.
Why are you selling sheep?
Don't bring it up.
I feel big cities don't suit me at all.
Our Kashgar is better.
How about you?
I heard
you're doing pretty well in Shanghai.
Not really.
Just average.
Our Arzugul
is now an executive at a
real estate company in Shanghai.
Don't listen to her nonsense.
You don't need to be modest.
You were always number one growing up.
I'm not surprised at all
that you're doing well.
How is Ms. Li?
She's fine.
My mom is retired now.
She travels around every day
and is rarely seen.
Are...
Are you married?
Who would I marry?
It's good enough
that I can support myself.
How long has it been
since we last saw each other?
7 years?
No.
It's been 7 years
since we graduated from high school.
But for us,
it will be 6 years in 2 months.
The last time we saw each other
was during the summer vacation
of our freshman year,
at the class reunion.
I remember you didn't come.
Right.
Let me add you on WeChat.
I only have your QQ,
and you're never online.
Are you two putting on
a blind date show in front of me?
Should I leave?
No.
We've been classmates for so many years.
Just adding WeChat.
Help!
The lamb was born not breathing.
Come, help!
Can someone help?
The lamb was born not breathing.
Here, give it to me.
Let me see.
Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Fang.
Mr. Fang, thanks to you.
The new-breed lambs you sent over
from your breeding base last time
are really good.
You're welcome.
Thank you.
Mr. Fang?
Aren't you a sheep seller?
A sheep seller?
No, no, no.
Mr. Fang is the youngest
engineer in our station.
He does scientific research,
and works on big projects.
He's amazing.
No.
I do sell sheep,
but our breeding base
isn't for money.
It's for data collection samples.
Can I hold it?
Sure.
Careful.
Be careful.
Like this.
Support its bottom with your hands.
Right.
I'm not very good at this.
It's okay. This works too.
Look at its nose bridge.
It's as high as Minawar's.
Its mother is calling it.
We're leaving, sir.
-Thank you.
-Bye.
It wasn't easy. He saved it.
We haven't seen each other for so long.
It's rare to run into you,
and I couldn't even treat you to a meal.
It's fine. We ate before coming.
Sir, let's go.
How...
How long are you staying this time?
I'll leave in a couple of days.
Well...
Alright.
I'm leaving.
Bye.
[Six years ago]
Fang Nan.
Is this almond necklace
for me?
It's for Xia Zi.
She's going to college in Shanghai.
She has seen so much of the world.
Would she even like this?
Did I remember it wrong?
Fang Nan said the last time we met was
at the class reunion that summer.
But I remember he didn't come.
Happy wedding.
A gift for you.
As soon as I saw this box,
I felt like it had your name on it.
Thank you.
I wish you happiness.
Did you use to like him?
You were the one who liked him.
There was absolutely nothing between us.
My fiance is so rich.
Who cares about Fang Nan?
Come, let's take a picture together.
Let's take it later.
Cheese.
Great.
Minawar!
You're going to Shanghai now.
Are you ignoring us?
I am not.
I texted you, but you didn't reply.
Tell me how you've been.
I...
am joining the regional
song and dance troupe.
Weren't you going to
apply for the dance academy
and coming to Shanghai to find me?
Not everyone is as lucky as you are,
Xia Zi.
Hey, you're here.
A book says that
in this world,
there are only two types of people.
Those who leave,
and those who stay.
Back then,
I left.
My hometown and friends
were all left behind.
Now,
I am a bit envious of
the friends who stayed.
Mom.
Adili.
I encountered a mudslide on the mountain.
Sorry to make you worry.
Mom.
Count them. See if any are missing.
Adili,
what are you doing?
What are you thinking?
She's getting married.
Why are you more persistent
than the wind in the Gobi?
No matter how deep your feelings are,
you can't move someone
who has made up their mind.
None of your business.
Go home.
This is the handmade chocolate
you asked me to bring.
Thank you.
How much is it? I'll transfer it to you.
No need. It's very cheap.
I can't just take it.
You always bring things for me.
It's no trouble at all.
How have you been
lately?
I've been good.
Do you know
who I ran into the other day?
Fang Nan.
Fang Nan?
I ran into him with Arzugul.
When I saw him that day,
I felt like we were back in our childhood.
I remember
you and Arzugul had a falling out
because of Fang Nan back then, right?
Stop thinking that girls only fight
over men, okay?
Men aren't that important.
But I see that you two have been
at odds all these years.
Back then, Fang Nan always
hung out with us to pursue Arzugul.
I thought he liked me.
It's that simple.
That simple?
Later,
Arzugul went to college
in Shanghai,
stayed there,
and then bought a house there.
And I
have always been here,
unable to go anywhere.
I'm inferior to her in every way.
You've never been inferior to Arzugul.
I've always said so,
but you just never believed it.
Let me try this candy.
If it's good,
I'll buy a lot for the gifts
at my wedding.
You must
come early to my wedding.
New city,
new beginning.
Sir,
can I help you?
Who are you?
Where's Wang?
This is my shop.
-He rented it to me.
-Your shop?
Yes, and now I run this guesthouse.
To you?
I am the landlord.
Leave.
No, sir.
You must be mistaken.
He said he rented this
from you for 5 years.
We just signed the contract.
Contract?
I won't look at it.
The lease has expired, no more renting.
Sir, I've already paid.
I gave him 100,000 a year.
What?
You can take a look.
100,000?
He only gave me 30,000!
Leave.
Go away.
-Sir, I've paid the rent.
-Leave.
Leave.
I have the transfer record.
Sir, is there a misunderstanding?
Sir!
Leave.
Wait, sir.
Leave
Go away.
Mom.
Mom!
Wake up.
You scared me.
How are you so strong?
You pressed so hard. My chest hurts.
What are you doing?
You scared me.
Right. Don't speak yet.
I'm afraid I'd forget.
Let me write it down.
It has an analgesic effect.
If you take too much, it will have
a sedative and sleep-inducing effect.
Are you playing
Shennong tasting the herbs?
What else?
Once your father died,
your mother has to seek death too?
Don't worry.
I'm not that fragile.
Why are you back?
I...
I'm going back to Shanghai soon.
I came back to keep you company.
Why are there so many flowers suddenly?
Look.
These Panax notoginseng,
mint, honeysuckle,
each one is a treasure.
Birth, aging, sickness and death
are like the rotation of the four seasons,
all natural laws.
We should let go of your father's matter.
Mom.
Regarding my father's death,
I really can't accept
his sudden departure.
I am not as detached as you,
nor as open-minded.
I can't let go so quickly.
Seeing you tough it out like this
makes me feel even worse.
Your father,
a man of over 80 kg,
was brought back in such a light box.
Do you think my heart doesn't hurt?
Take this.
I still have to
revise prescriptions tonight.
You don't have to come all the way here.
Go back.
I've been used to being alone
for so many years.
Just go back to Shanghai
with peace of mind.
Life still has to go on.
I still have a bunch of
little babies to take care of.
Hello, Mr. Li.
You're still up so late.
Have you sorted out the things at home?
Yes, I have.
Rest assured.
I'll definitely hurry up to make up for
the unfinished work
from before these days.
I have a client
who really likes
the Yengisar knives from here.
I bought one for him this time.
There is something
I need to inform you about.
Go ahead.
Recently, the company
has made structural adjustments,
decided to reduce costs, increase
efficiency, and cut sales positions.
It's not that I haven't warned you before.
Your team
has been at the bottom
in performance more than once.
I've told you so many times,
but there's no improvement.
Everyone competes fairly.
Eliminating the worst performers
is company policy.
Come back as soon as possible
and handle your resignation.
Hello, the number you dialed...
Wang, answer the phone.
It's Zhou Hengzhi!
You know me?
Poor guy.
You rented an empty house
from the old miser Mehmet,
and were scammed out of 100,000 yuan
by your best friend.
H-how did you know?
Of course we know.
Our friend Abudu told us.
Oh, please.
Don't be angry.
Anger feeds the devil.
Don't worry.
Worry makes you die early.
Don't be anxious.
Hi.
What a coincidence.
Are you here...
for a walk?
Want to walk together?
I'm hungry.
So,
you paid all the money,
and your friend ran away?
Who said
he wanted to be
the missing piece of the puzzle?
I admit, I was slapped in the face.
Okay?
You're talking about me?
You're not any better yourself.
You lost your job.
Are you going back?
Of course I have to.
If I don't go back, who will pay me?
Who will pay my mortgage?
I think
we can celebrate.
What to celebrate? Things are like this.
No.
Since things are this bad,
they can't get any worse, right?
What's that inspirational quote again?
Once you pick up
all the stones at the bottom,
the rest of your life
is an upward journey.
You're quite good at it.
You want some?
Chopsticks.
What are you looking at?
Look.
Who said things couldn't get worse?
Rose Garden's construction suspended.
Resumption date to be notified.
Is it the house you bought?
Even if things are worse,
this noodle
is not too bad.
So this is how you cheer yourself up?
Three, two, one, cheese!
♪ An empty bowl is enough ♪
♪ I'll take it as my wine cup ♪
♪ My only confidants now ♪
♪ Are these four lonely walls ♪
♪ The sound of the dutar ♪
♪ Has already drunk my heart ♪
♪ I play my instrument with care ♪
♪ So the neighbors won't be aware ♪
♪ Take the world, I give it to you ♪
♪ Just leave me my lonely,
sorrowful tune ♪
♪ The dutar is my lover ♪
♪ The dutar is my wine ♪
♪ The dutar is where my hangovers begin ♪
♪ Let everyone stay away ♪
♪ Leave me here alone ♪
♪ In grief, in sorrow, in the cold ♪
Don't be angry.
♪ My lover is my wine ♪
Anger feeds the devil.
♪ My lover is where my hangovers begin ♪
Let me ask you something.
The other day,
I saw you at the grand bazaar.
Who was that boy?
He seemed to know you very well.